

# CONTACI

- 0728726668
- youngbk0308@gmail.com
- 63 Olive Road, EASTRIDGE, Mitchell's Plain, 7785
- https://bit.ly/3SXCMej



https://byron-young-portfoliov2.vercel.app/

## **EDUCATION**

Jan 2021 - Dec 2023

Cape Peninsula University of **Technology** 

**DPICTADIP: ICT in Applications** Development

Jan 2008 - Dec 2012

**Princeton High School** 

National Senior Certificate

## TECH STACKS



English (Fluent)

# BYRON YOUNG

# JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### **PROFILE**

Junior software developer with two years' experience in a software development environment. I have completed my diploma in Information & Communication Technology at Cape Peninsula University of Technology. I am an excellent communicator, problem solver, and team player. My career objective is to become a Full Stack Developer, as I am constantly seeking opportunities to learn new technologies to improve my skills. I am excited to bring my skills and passion to a new role in the field of software development.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

- Cape Peninsula University of Technology JULY 2023 - DEC 2023 Intern Developer
  - Assisted in editing and maintaining project documentation.
  - Developed a Virtual Machine request application.
  - · Worked with team members using GitHub for version control and collaboration.

#### **University of Western Cape**

MAY 2018 - MAY 2019

Intern Developer

- · Worked closely with a senior developer to design and implement an application utilizing SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS).
- · Assisted in documentation and quality assurance processes.
- Collaborating with team members on GitHub.

#### Web 2 Web

MAY 2017 - NOV 2017

Intern Web Developer

- Designed and developed webpages for clients, ensuring responsiveness and functionality.
- Managed and updated website content to align with client requirements.
- Implemented SEO best practices to enhance client online visibility.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Good Eats Restaurant ASP.NET MVC Web Application

I developed a restaurant order web application using ASP.NET MVC and Razor Pages, utilizing Microsoft SQL Server for database management. ASP.NET Identity was implemented for secure authentication and role-based authorization. Sessions have been integrated into user-specific cart tracking, enabling easy ordering. I designed a user-friendly interface to allow customers to browse menus and place orders, along with a dashboard for administrators to manage their menus and orders.

#### REFERENCE

#### **Ageel Bucks**

University of Western Cape

**Position:** Senior Developer

Phone: 0613548781

# Malibongwe Dywibiba

Cape Peninsula University of Technology

Position: ICT Department Supervisor

Phone: 083 494 2638